Welcome.
欢迎。
In the last lecture, we successfully set up a debug helper for us to print debug messages
在上一节课中，我们成功地设置了一个调试助手，让我们在屏幕上打印调试信息
to the screen.
到屏幕上。
And starting from this lecture, let's look at how we can actually set up our climbing
从这节课开始，让我们来看看如何实际设置我们的爬行
system.
系统。
So basically, in order to achieve what we want, there are three steps that we need.
所以基本上，为了实现我们想要的东西，我们需要三个步骤。
First, we need to enable climbing.
首先，我们需要启用攀爬功能。
After that, it will be character climb.
之后，将是角色攀登。
Then it will be character stop climbing.
然后将是角色停止攀爬。
This is an overly simplified process.
这是一个过于简化的过程。
There are actually many things that we need to handle in between these stages.
实际上，在这些阶段之间，有许多事情我们需要处理。
Take character climb for example.
以角色攀爬为例。
There will be many cases that we shouldn't be able to start climbing.
会有很多情况下，我们不应该开始攀爬。
And there are also many cases that we should stop climbing.
也有很多情况下，我们应该停止攀登。
For example, when our character already reached the ledge or the floor, either way we should
例如，当我们的角色已经到达壁架或地板时，无论如何我们都应该
stop climbing right away.
马上停止攀爬。
We are going to handle off those later.
我们将在后面处理这些问题。
For now, let's just look at how we should enable our climbing.
现在，让我们来看看我们应该如何启用我们的攀爬。
And I like to do that through input.
我喜欢通过输入来做这件事。
Go back to my project.
回到我的项目中去。
First, I'm going to close my project.
首先，我将关闭我的项目。
Then go back to Visual Studio.
然后再回到Visual Studio。
I'm going to go to my character's header file.
我将转到我的角色的头文件。
And if you scroll up, you can see by default, there are already many input actions set up.
如果你向上滚动，你可以看到在默认情况下，已经有许多输入动作被设置了。
So the default mapping context here, this is where we set up the key binding.
所以这里的默认映射上下文，这就是我们设置按键绑定的地方。
Unlike the old input system that needs us to set up the key binding in project settings,
不像以前的输入系统，需要我们在项目设置中设置按键绑定、
and we also need to have individual input actions for us to bind to the keys and the
而且我们还需要有单独的输入动作来绑定我们需要的键和
functions that we need.
我们需要的功能。
This is actually a very powerful system that allows us to add or remove keys during runtime.
这实际上是一个非常强大的系统，它允许我们在运行时添加或删除键。
And we can even switch between different mapping contexts if we want.
如果我们愿意，我们甚至可以在不同的映射上下文之间切换。
And if you scroll down, these are the two functions that bind to these two actions.
如果你往下看，这是与这两个动作绑定的两个函数。
So inside of my cpp file, you can see for the move function, it's binding to this move
所以在我的cpp文件中，你可以看到移动函数，它被绑定到这个移动
action.
动作。
And this is our jump action.
而这是我们的跳跃动作。
We are going to handle all of these movement code differently when we are climbing.
当我们在攀爬时，我们将以不同的方式处理所有这些运动代码。
So now I just want to set up a key that enables the character to start climbing.
所以现在我只想设置一个键，使角色开始爬升。
So go back to my header file.
所以回到我的头文件中去。
First I'm going to organize the order of these functions.
首先我要组织这些函数的顺序。
So I'm going to move this constructor to the top of the header file and move this generality
所以我要把这个构造函数移到头文件的顶部，把这个通用的
body to the top.
体移到顶部。
Then I'm going to set up a private section.
然后我将设置一个私有部分。
Then scroll down, I'm going to delete this protected.
然后向下滚动，我将删除这个受保护的部分。
So I want these two functions to be private as well.
所以我希望这两个函数也是私有的。
Then I'm going to adjust the order of the move function.
然后我将调整移动函数的顺序。
So I'm going to cut it and move it to be below this move action.
所以我要把它剪掉，然后把它移到这个移动动作的下面。
Then I'm going to set up a new input action.
然后，我将设置一个新的输入动作。
So I'm going to copy these two lines, control plus C and control plus V to put it in here.
所以我要复制这两行，控制加C和控制加V，把它放在这里。
Instead of loop action, I'm going to change this to climb action.
我将改变这个动作，而不是循环动作，改为爬升动作。
And I'm going to create a function for us to bind to this input action.
我将创建一个函数，让我们与这个输入动作绑定。
I'm going to call this function on climb action started and it needs one input parameter.
我将在爬升动作开始时调用这个函数，它需要一个输入参数。
There will be this input action value.
将会有这个输入动作的值。
So I'm going to copy this and paste it in here.
所以我要复制这个并把它粘贴到这里。
And I'm going to create a function definition and paste the function to be below this look.
我将创建一个函数定义，并将该函数粘贴到这个外观的下面。
First thing I'm going to set up the key binding inside of this function, set up player input
首先，我要在这个函数中设置密钥绑定，设置播放器输入组件。
component.
组件。
So I'm going to copy this line and I'm going to paste it in here.
所以我要复制这一行并把它粘贴到这里。
Now instead of loop action, this will be our climb action.
现在，代替循环动作，这将是我们的爬升动作。
So I'm going to copy this and paste it in here.
所以我要复制这句话并把它粘贴到这里。
Now for this trigger event, instead of triggered, I'm going to change it to something else.
现在，对于这个触发事件，我将把它改成其他的东西，而不是触发的。
So I'm going to delete this and type in colon colon.
所以我将删除这个，然后输入冒号。
You can see in here there are many stages that we can choose.
你可以看到这里有很多阶段，我们可以选择。
If this is triggered, the function that's bound to this input action will be constantly
如果这个被触发了，绑定在这个输入动作上的函数就会被不断地触发
triggered as long as the input key is down.
只要输入键不动，就会被触发。
But that's not what I want for our climb action.
但这不是我想要的我们的攀登行动。
I'm going to change this to start it.
我要把这个改为启动它。
So now we are only able to trigger this action once, even if the key is down.
所以现在我们只能触发这个动作一次，即使按键是向下的。
Then I'm going to change the function to the function that I just created.
然后我要把这个函数改为我刚刚创建的函数。
So scroll down and I'm going to copy this one and I'm going to paste it in here.
所以向下滚动，我要复制这个，并把它粘贴到这里。
Then I'm going to press control plus B to compile.
然后我将按控制键加B来编译。
Now let's look at how we should implement the function.
现在让我们来看看我们应该如何实现这个函数。
So scroll down till this on climb action is started.
所以向下滚动，直到这个在攀登动作开始。
So by pressing the button, I like to enable or disable climbing.
所以通过按下按钮，我喜欢启用或禁用爬升。
We're going to handle that later.
我们将在后面处理这个问题。
Now I just want to print a message to the screen to prove this key binding is working.
现在我只想在屏幕上打印一条信息，以证明这个按键绑定是有效的。
So scroll up to the begin play.
所以向上滚动到开始播放。
I'm going to cut this debug line and I'm going to move it to here.
我要剪下这个调试行，把它移到这里。
I'm going to change the message to climb action started.
我将把信息改为爬升动作开始。
Alright, I'm going to press control plus F5 to launch my editor.
好了，我要按控制键加F5来启动我的编辑器。
Go back to my project in order for the key binding to work.
回到我的项目中去，以便使键的绑定发挥作用。
There are still two more steps that we need to do.
还有两个步骤我们需要做。
So I'm going to go to this third person folder.
所以我要去这个第三人称文件夹。
You can see in there there's a folder called input.
你可以看到在那里有一个叫输入的文件夹。
I'm going to open it and this is the default mapping input context.
我将打开它，这是默认的映射输入上下文。
And inside of the actions folder, these are all the input actions.
而在行动文件夹里面，这些是所有的输入行动。
We'll need to create a new one.
我们需要创建一个新的。
So right mouse button click and go to input and select input action.
所以鼠标右键点击，进入输入，选择输入动作。
I'm going to call this action ia_climb.
我将把这个动作称为ia_climb。
Double click to open this input action.
双击来打开这个输入动作。
For a single key event, we do want this value type to be bool.
对于一个单键事件，我们确实希望这个值的类型是bool。
So the default setting will work in here.
所以默认设置在这里就可以了。
Then I'm going to go back to this input folder, open this mapping context and click this drop
然后我将回到这个输入文件夹，打开这个映射上下文，点击这个下拉菜单，显示所有现有的映射。
down to show all the existing mappings.
来显示所有现有的映射。
Now we need to add a new one.
现在我们需要添加一个新的。
So we can click this add button to add a new one and fill in our ia_climb.
所以我们可以点击这个添加按钮来添加一个新的，并填入我们的ia_climb。
And we can set up the key binding in here.
我们可以在这里设置密钥绑定。
So I'm going to press this keyboard.
所以我将按下这个键盘。
Then I'm going to use F to trigger the climbing.
然后我将使用F来触发攀登。
Alright that's the key binding done.
好了，这就完成了按键绑定。
There's still one more thing that we need to do.
还有一件事我们需要做。
So go back to my third person folder inside of blueprints.
所以请回到蓝图中的第三人称文件夹。
Double click to open this third person character.
双击来打开这个第三人称角色。
Remember our input action is just a pointer.
记住我们的输入动作只是一个指针。
In order for it to work, we need to also assign values inside of the blueprint class.
为了让它工作，我们还需要在蓝图类中赋值。
So I'm going to open this for blueprint editor and I'm going to type in input to search.
因此，我将打开这个蓝图编辑器，我将输入输入法来搜索。
And you can see these are the existing input actions.
你可以看到这些是现有的输入动作。
Now for the climb action, I'm going to fill in our ia_climb.
现在，对于爬升动作，我将填入我们的ia_climb。
And that's it.
就这样了。
I'm going to click compile and go back to my level.
我将点击编译并回到我的关卡。
I'm going to click play in here and I'm going to press F. You can see a debug message has
我将点击这里的播放，然后按F。
been printed to the screen and it says climb action started.
你可以看到一条调试信息被打印到屏幕上，上面写着攀登动作开始。
Alright, our key binding is working.
好了，我们的按键绑定工作完成了。
Later when you try to implement this by yourself, remember you need to create and assign this
以后当你尝试自己实现这个动作时，请记住你需要创建并指定这个
input action.
输入动作。
So that includes creating a variable inside of the header file and assigning the actual
因此，这包括在头文件中创建一个变量，并将实际的
object in the blueprint class.
对象在蓝图类中。
And don't forget to set up the key binding in the mapping context.
不要忘了在映射上下文中设置键的绑定。
Alright it's time to set up your own input action and I'll see you in the next lecture.
好了，现在是设置你自己的输入动作的时候了，我们在下一讲再见。
[music]
[音乐]